Guide to the Chris Kraus Papers MSS.442
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II. Films, 1980-2015; 24 Linear Feet in 15 record cartons, 10 manuscript boxes, 7 flat boxes, 1 media box, and 1 flat file folder; 77 audiocassettes in 60 compact audio cassettes, 14 DAT cassettes, and 3 micro-cassettes; 45 videocassettes in 11 VHS cassettes, 30 Umatic cassettes, 3 Betacam 
  - Gravity and Grace -- Paper, Born-digital, and Audiovisual Materials, 1992-2015; cuid36455; 20 film reels in 20 16mm film reels; 18 audiocassettes; 15 videocassettes in 5 VHS cassettes, 7 UMatic cassettes, 3 Betacam cassettes; 1 videoreels (1 inch); 37 sound tape reels in 37 1/4" audio reels; 13 sound cassettes (dat) (Box 59, Box 60, Box 61, Box 63, Box 64, Box 65, Box 66, Box 68, Box 77, Folder 9-12, Box 78, Folder 1-13, Box 79, Folder 1-2, Box 86, Box 88, Box Shared Fales 028, Folder 3, Box Shared Fales 020, Folder 5-6, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_442_ER_17, Reel MSS.442.cuid36455, Box 97, Vhs 442_0019, U-matic 442_0028, 442_0035-442_0037)
  - Gravity and Grace -- Video Reel, 1995; cuid7006 (Box 59, Reel MSS.442.cuid7006)
    Original Format: 1" Type C Open Reel Video [Master], Duration: 88 min., Color, Sound
  - Home videos, undated (Box 97, Vhs 442_0017)
  - Hours 1 and 2, undated (Box 97, U-matic 442_0033)
  - How to Shoot a Crime -- Paper, Born-digital, and Audiovisual Materials, 1982-2015; 5 audiocassettes; 1 videodisc (dvd); 4 videocassettes 2 VHS cassettes, 2 UMatic cassettes; 1 film reels in 1 Super 8 reel (Box 60, Box 62, Box 83, Folder 11-20, Box 84, Folder 1, Box 86, Box 92, Folder 2, Flat-file-folder 3, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_442_ER_18, Box 101, U-matic 442_0040)
  - In Order to Pass -- Damages [Optical Print] -- Film Reel, 1982; cuid6298 (Reel MSS.442.cuid6298)
    16mm [Print], Silent
  - In Order to Pass -- Digitized Video, 1982; cuid6299 (Box Electronic Records, File MSS.442.cuid6299, Box 65, Cassette mss.442.cuid6299)
    Housing annotations read: Pt. 2 Transfer master.
    3/4" Umatic [Master], 8 min.
  - In Order to Pass -- Paper and Born-digital Materials, and Films, 1982-2015; 6 film reels 6 Super 8 film reels (Box 62, Box 83, Folder 6-10, Box Shared Fales 028, Folder 5, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_442_ER_19)
  - In Order to Pass -- Video, undated (Box 97, U-matic 442_0038)
  - Judy Nylon -- Video, undated (Box 95, U-matic 442_0008, Box 97, Vhs 442_0024)
  - Kid poems, undated (Box 97, Vhs 442_0021)
  - [Little Room] ?, Undated; cuid36457 (Box 98, 16mm film reels MSS.442.cuid36547)
  - Looking for Suzanne, 2011-2015 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_442_ER_50)
  - Message Units, 1992 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_442_ER_33, Box 79, Folder 6)
  - The Middle Ages, 1986; 2 videocassettes (u-matic) (Box 70)
  - Miron, undated; 1 videoreels (1 inch) (Box 101, 1 inch video reel 442_0041)
  - The Pact, 1992-2015 (Box 82, Folder 1-7, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_442_ER_22)
  - Party, Undated; 2 film reels in 2 Super 8 film reels; 2 videocassettes (u-matic) (Box 71, Box 73)
  - Puppet show, November 27, 1989 (Box 97, Vhs 442_0022)
  - Sadness at Leaving, 1987-1993; cuid36456; 13 videocassettes in 8 U-Matic cassettes, 3 VHS cassettes, and 2 1-inch video reel; 7 audiocassettes; 1 sound cassettes (dat); 8 film reels (Box 60, Box 75, Box 8-14, Box 76, Folder 1-9, Box 77, Folder 1-8, Box 86, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_442_ER_20, Box 98, 16mm film reels MSS.442.cuid36456a to MSS.442.cuid36456h, Box 96, U-matic 442_0001, 442_0002, 442_0004, 422_0005, 442_0007, 442_0009-442_0016,, Box 95, U-matic 442_0007, 442_0009-442_0016, Box 102, 1 inch video reel 442_0045, Box 101, Vhs 442_0044)
  - Show David and Gent, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 442_0031)
  - Simone Weil, 1988-1989 (Box 81, Folder 10)
  - Speaking Engagements, 2007 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_442_ER_21, Box 97)
  - Suzan Day CA, undated (Box 97, Betamax 442_0026-442_0027)
  - Stony Creek, undated (Box 97, U-matic 442_0034)
  - Terrorists in Love -- Film Reel, 1983; cuid6295 (Box Shared Fales 061, Reel MSS.442.cuid6295)
    16mm [Print], Sound, Color, 5 min. 30 sec.
  - Terrorists in Love -- Film Reel, 1983; cuid6294 (Box Shared Fales 049, Reel MSS.442.cuid6294E, Box Shared Fales 061, Reel MSS.442.cuid6294, MSS.442.cuid6294A, MSS.442.cuid6294B, MSS.442.cuid6294C, MSS.442.cuid6294D)
    Super8mm [Print], Silent, BW, 5 min. 30 sec.
  - Terrorists in Love -- Paper and Film Materials, Undated; 1 Reels in 1 16mm film reel (Box 66, Box 82, Folder 8)
  - Terrorists in Love, 1983; cuid7002 (Box 96, U-matic MSS.442.cuid7002, Box 101, U-matic 442_0042)
    3/4" Umatic, 5 min.
  - Terrorists in Love and A True Story -- Digitized Video, 1983; 2018; cuid6296 (Box Electronic Records, File MSS.442.cuid6296, Box 70)
    Housing annotations read: "original formats: 'Terrorists', S8; 'True Story', 16mm".
    3/4" Umatic [Master], 20 min.
  - Travelling at Night -- Paper and Audiovisual Materials, 1980-1991; 1 videocassettes (vhs); 2 audiocassettes (Box 60, Box 80, Folder 5-6, Box 84, Folder 2-8, Box 85, Box 101)
  - Travelling at Night -- Videocassettes, 1990; cuid7123 (Box 96, Cassette MSS.442.cuid7123, Box 95, U-matic MSS.442.cuid7006, Box 101, 1 inch video reel 442_0039, 442_0046)
    3/4" Umatic, 60 min.
  - Unidentified Films -- Audiovisual and Born-digital Materials, Undated; 20 audiocassettes in 17 compact audio cassettes, 3 micro-cassettes; 130 film reels in 17 16mm film reels, 112 Super 8 film reels; 6 videocassettes 1 Betamax cassette, 5 UMatic cassettes; 2 sound tape reels in 2 1/4" reels (Box 61, Box 67, Box 69, Box 72, Box 73, Box 74, Box 85, Box 86, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_442_ER_34, Box 96, U-matic 442_0006, Box 97, Vhs 442_0018)
  - Unidentified Films -- Raw workprint, Undated; cuid36458 (Box 98, 16mm film reels MSS.442.cuid36548)
  - Unidentified Films -- Workprint with flagged notes, Undated; cuid36459 (Box 98, 16mm film reels MSS.422.cuid36459)
  - Voyage to Rodez -- Film Reel, 1986; cuid6297 (Box Shared Fales 048, Reel 6297A, 6297B, 6297C, Box Shared Fales 060, Reel cuid6297, cuid6297D)
    16mm [Print], Sound, BW, 14 min.
  - Voyage to Rodez -- Paper and Audiovisual Materials, 17 film reels in 17 Super 8 film reels; 1 audiocassette (Box 62, Box 83, Folder 4, Box 85)
  - Will all scenes, undated (Box 97, Quarter inch audio reel 442_0030)
- Series III. Diaries, 1975-2015; 6.5 Linear Feet in 12 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, and 1 record carton; 2 videocassettes (vhs); 277 kilobytes in 9 documents
  Conditions Governing Access
  Donor permission is required for access. Please contact the Fales Library & Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2596.
  This series is arranged in chronological order.
  This series contains over 80 diaries documenting Kraus's life from 1975 through 2015. This series consists mainly of paper diaries in bound volumes, with some loose paper entries, born-digital entries, and video recordings. The diaries include her feelings about her personal and professional lives and early notes and drafts of her work. Included in this series are some of Kraus's diaries created during the project between Kraus and Lotringer that led to the publication of I Love Dick; diaries kept during her work on other publications, including Torpor; and diaries kept during the production of her film Gravity and Grace. Some diaries contain a few entries and some are completely filled with entries. Kraus identified some diaries by date spans, some by location, and others by project title.
  - Diaries -- 1970s, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1-9, Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Diaries -- 1980s, 1981-1989 (Box 2, Folder 1-11, Box 26, Folder 1-4)
  - Diaries -- 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 1-11, Box 4, Folder 1-8, Box 5, Folder 1-9, Box 6, Folder 1-3, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_442_ER_23)
  - Diaries -- 2000s, 2000-2015 (Box 6, Folder 4-6, Box 7, Folder 1-6, Box 8, Box 9, Box 10, Folder 1-5, Box 11, Folder 1-7, Box 12, Folder 1-9, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_442_ER_24)
  - Diaries -- Video, Undated; 2 videocassettes (vhs) (Box 60)
- Series IV. Correspondence, 1976-2015; 2 Linear Feet in 4 manuscript boxes and 1 half manuscript box; 273.5 Megabytes in 34 computer files; 5.3 Gigabytes in 23 email archives
  Donor permission is required for access to correspondence in box 91 and to all email files. Please contact the Fales Library & Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2596.
  Paper material in this series was brought together physically, but has not been further arranged by an archivist. Email files in this series have not been arranged by an archivist and are in the order in which they were received from the donor.
  This series consists of general correspondence between Kraus and friends, collaborators, and acquaintances, spanning from 1975 to 2015. These include paper and email correspondence, as well as word processing drafts of letters. Topics include daily life, as well as current and proposed projects. Correspondents include Hedi El Kholti, Justin Cavin, Tamar Brott, David Farrar, Ruth Novaczek, Moyra Davey, Jim Fletcher, Bernadette Van Huy and John Kelsey (Bernadette Corporation), Bob Glück, Gary Indiana, Sylvère Lotringer, Eileen Myles, Lynne Tillman, Penny Arcade, and Sheila Heti.
  - Correspondence, 1976-2015 (Box 79, Folder 8-15, Box 84, Folder 9-16, Box 87, Folder 1-16, Box 89, Folder 1-9, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_442_ER_25)
  - Email Files, 2004-2015 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_442_ER_27)
    Donor permission required for access. Please contact the Fales Library & Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
  - Restricted Correspondence, 1985-2003 (Box 91, Folder 1-2)
- Series V. The Chance Event, 1993-2015; 1.7 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 1 half manuscript box, and 2 flat boxes; 1 audiocassette in 1 micro-cassette
  Material in this series was brought together physically and rehoused, but has not been further arranged by an archivist.
  Historical Note
  The Chance Event was a festival curated by Kraus and held in Nevada in 1996. The focus of the event focused on the idea of chance and included discussions and performances with visual artists, musicians, and others, including Jean Baudrillard, Rosanne Allucquère Stone, DJ Spooky, and Diane DiPrima.
  This series contains paper material and an audio recording documenting The Chance Event, particularly the planning of the event by Kraus in 1996. The series includes a catalog of sessions at the event, drafts of material used in the event, photographs of the event, and a mini audio cassette from Kraus' answering machine with messages from event participants.
  - The Chance Event, 1993-2015; cuid36383; 1 audiocassette in 1 micro-cassette (Box 86, Box 89, Folder 10-14, Box 90, Folder 1-5, Box Shared Fales 020, Folder 7)